# **CURTIS LANE**

Sanford, FL 32773 | Phone: (321) 277-8397 | Email: <a href="mailto:claneImt@gmail.com">claneImt@gmail.com</a> | <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/curtislane-/">https://www.linkedin.com/in/curtislane-/</a> | Portfolio: <a href="https://curtislane.github.io/Portfolio/">https://curtislane.github.io/Portfolio/</a>

### **SUMMARY**

Full stack developer with 2+ years of experience developing web applications and mobile responsive websites. Proven skills in language learning, problem solving, time management, verbal and nonverbal communication, and ongoing education. Recognized for outstanding team collaboration and results-focused, high quality work.

### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

React | Node.JS | MongoDB | MySQL | Express | Sequelize | Mongoose | HTML5 | CSS3 | ES6 | Bootstrap | Python

#### RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

### Teaching Assistant - UCF Full Stack Boot Camp - 2U/Trilogy Education

2020 - current

- Offer individual support and instruction to students by hosting group sessions related to web development
- Teach technical skills including MongoDB, MySQL, Express, React, Node, Javascript, ES6, CSS3, HTML5, and more using up to date curriculum designed by industry experts.
- Work in collaboration with instructional team to motivate, encourage, and guide students to succeed as future developers.

### Freelance Web Developer

2017 - current

- Designed a customized website using Wordpress, HTML, and CSS to market Personal Training business featuring landing, about, and contact pages with call to action resulting in online client acquisition
- Created and maintained informative health and fitness blog using WordPress to help inform clients with the latest information in the industry.
- Designed fitness web application with React.js, MongoDB, Mongoose, Express, Node.js to help users stay active at home during isolation by designing their own custom workouts.

## **PROJECTS**

HomeBody Fitness | https://github.com/CurtisLane/Homebody | https://homebody-fitness.herokuapp.com/

- Full stack MERN application which allows users to log in using OAuth, generate custom workouts, and save workouts to their profile for later use.
- Responsibilities: created the database seed, wrote algorithm to generate workouts based on user input, connected front to back end with API's, and designed functional components that utilize global hooks.

Droplet | https://github.com/CurtisLane/droplet | https://project-droplet.herokuapp.com/

- Droplet is a simple social media platform for users to create a profile, post content, and make comments..
- Responsibilities: Connected back end with front end using jQuery, styled elements with Bootstrap, and wrote professional readme.

Dinner and a Movie github.com/CurtisLane/Dinner-and-a-Movie | curtislane.github.io/Dinner-and-a-Movie

- Dinner and a Movie allows users to search for recipes and top trending movies on the same page.
- Responsibilities: Managed agile project workflow, set up external API's with Ajax, displayed results dynamically with jQuery, implemented Animate on Scroll and Lettering.js libraries, and styling with CSS3.

#### **EDUCATION**

### University of Central Florida - Full-Stack Web Development Certificate Orlando, FL

2020

An intensive 6-month project-based boot camp focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, NodeJs, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, & ReactJS.

#### **Independent Coursework/Research**

2018 - 2020

Private Instruction/Mentorship, Python | Sep, 2020 - Oct, 2020 Udemy, Full Stack Web Developer Boot Camp | Feb, 2019 - Jul, 2019 Free Code Camp, HTML CSS and JavaScript | Oct, 2018 - Jan, 2019